and he himself was that Adam with his finger outstretched and not quite touching that God's hand. Mastery is in the reaching, not the arriving. It's in constantly wanting to close that gap between where you are and where you want to be. Mastery is about sacrificing for your craft and not for the sake of crafting your career. How many inventors and untold entrepreneurs live out this phenomenon? We see it even in the life of the indomitable Arctic explorer Ben Saunders, who tells me that his triumphs are not merely the result of a grand achievement, but of the propulsion of a lineage of near wins. We thrive when we stay at our own leading edge. It's a wisdom understood by Duke Ellington, who said that his favorite song out of his repertoire was always the next one, always the one he had yet to compose. Part of the reason that the near win is inbuilt to mastery is because the greater our proficiency, the more clearly we might see that we don't know all that we thought we did. It's called the Dunning–Kruger effect. The Paris Review got it out of James Baldwin when they asked him, "What do you think increases with knowledge?" and he said, "You learn how little you know." Success motivates us, but a near win can propel us in an ongoing quest. One of the most vivid examples of this comes when we look at the difference between Olympic silver medalists and bronze medalists after a competition. Thomas Gilovich and his team from Cornell studied this difference and found that the frustration silver medalists feel compared to bronze, who are typically a bit more happy to have just not received fourth place and not medaled at all, gives silver medalists a focus on follow-up competition. We see it even in the gambling industry that once picked up on this phenomenon of the near win and created these scratch-off tickets that had a higher than average rate of near wins and so compelled people to buy more tickets that they were called heart-stoppers, and were set on a gambling industry set of abuses in Britain in the 1970s. The reason the near win has a propulsion is because it changes our view of the landscape and puts our goals, which we tend to put at a distance, into more proximate vicinity to where we stand. If I ask you to envision what a great day looks like next week, you might describe it in more general terms. But if I ask you to describe a great day at TED tomorrow, you might describe it with granular, practical clarity. And this is what a near win does. It gets us to focus on what, right now, we plan to do to address that mountain in our sights. It's Jackie Joyner-Kersee, who in 1984 missed taking the gold in the heptathlon by one third of a second, and her husband predicted that would give her the tenacity she needed in follow-up competition. In 1988, she won the gold in the heptathlon and set a record of 7,291 points, a score that no athlete has come very close to since. We thrive not when we've done it all, but when we still have more to do. I stand here thinking and wondering about all the different ways that we might even manufacture a near win in this room, how your lives might play this out, because I think on some gut level we do know this. We know that we thrive when we stay at our own leading edge, and it's why the deliberate incomplete is inbuilt into creation myths. In Navajo culture, some craftsmen and women would deliberately put an imperfection in textiles and ceramics. It's what's called a spirit line, a deliberate flaw in the pattern to give the weaver or maker a way out, but also a reason to continue making work. Masters are not experts because they take a subject to its conceptual end. They're masters because they realize that there isn't one. Now it occurred to me, as I thought about this, why the archery coach told me at the end of that practice, out of earshot of his archers, that he and his colleagues never feel they can do enough for their team, never feel there are enough visualization techniques and posture drills to help them overcome those constant near wins. It didn't sound like a complaint, exactly, but just a way to let me know, a kind of tender admission, to remind me that he knew he was giving himself over to a voracious, unfinished path that always required more. We build out of the unfinished idea, even if that idea is our former self. This is the dynamic of mastery. Coming close to what you thought you wanted can help you attain more than you ever dreamed you could. It's what I have to imagine Elizabeth Murray was thinking when I saw her smiling at those early paintings one day in the galleries. Even if we created utopias, I believe we would still have the incomplete. Completion is a goal, but we hope it is never the end. Thank you. (Applause)
como si él mismo fuera ese Adán con su dedo buscando y casi tocando la mano de Dios. La maestría es el buscar, no el llegar. Es la búsqueda constante de cerrar la brecha entre lo que se es y lo que se quiere ser. La maestría es sacrificarse por su arte y no por hacer una carrera. ¿Cuántos inventores y emprendedores anónimos viven esto? Vemos esto incluso en la vida del explorador del ártico Ben Saunders que me dijo que su triunfo no es únicamente el resultado de un gran logro, sino el resultado de una cadena de casi lograrlo. Progresamos cuando superamos nuestros límites. Es una sabiduría que entendió Duke Ellington cuando dijo que su canción favorita de su repertorio era siempre la siguiente, siempre la que aún no componía. Parte de la razón del casi lograrlo en lograr la maestría es porque a mayor sea nuestro desempeño, más claramente podemos ver que no sabemos todo lo que creíamos. Se le llama el efecto Dunning-Kruger. James Baldwin, cuando le preguntaron para The Paris Review, "¿Qué crees que incrementa el conocimiento?" respondió "Aprender que sabes muy poco". El éxito nos motiva, pero el casi lograrlo nos catapulta a una búsqueda constante. Uno de los ejemplos más vívidos de esto es cuando vemos la diferencia entre los medallístas olímpicos de plata y los de bronce después de la competencia. Thomas Gilovich y su equipo de Cornell estudiaron esta diferencia y encontraron que la frustración que sufren los ganadores de plata comparada con la de los de bronce, que están un poco más felices no haber llegado en cuarto lugar y no ganar ninguna medalla, les da a los ganadores de la plata un objetivo para mejorar en la competencia. Vemos esto incluso en la industria de las apuestas en el que aplicamos este fenómeno del casi lograrlo y creamos los billetes de rascar que tiene un promedio de casi ganadores mayor y así compelemos a que compren más billetes que se conocen como ganafáciles y se utilizó en la serie de abusos de la industria de apuestas en Inglaterra durante la década de los 70s. La razón del porqué casi ganar da esta propulsión es porque cambia nuestra manera de ver las cosas y pone nuestras metas, a las que tendemos a poner a la distancia, más cerca de donde estamos. Si les pidiera que pensaran cómo sería un gran día la próxima semana lo describirían en términos generales. Pero si les preguntara cómo sería un gran día en el TED de mañana puede que lo describan con claridad granular y práctica. Y esto es lo que el casi lograrlo hace. Nos hace concentrarnos, en este momento, en lo que planeamos para alcanzar las estrellas. Es Jackie Joyner-Kersee, que en 1984 perdió el oro en heptatlón por un tercio de segundo y su esposo predijo que eso le daría la tenacidad para seguir en la competencia En 1988 ganó el oro en heptatlón e impondría una marca de 7291 puntos, una marca a la que ningún atleta se ha acercado desde entonces. Progresamos no cuando ya hicimos todo, sino cuando aún hay algo por hacer. Pienso e imagino en las distintas formas de casi lograrlo en este salón, cómo sus vidas lo tomarían, porque creo que en cierto nivel lo sabemos. Sabemos que progresamos cuando estamos en nuestro propio límite y es por eso que la incompetencia deliberada está en la creación de los mitos. En la cultura navajo, algunos artesanos y mujeres deliberadamente ponen imperfecciones en sus textiles y cerámicas. Es lo que se llama una línea de espíritu, un error deliberado en el patrón para mostrar el creador o al tejedor, pero también una razón para seguir trabajando. Los maestros no son expertos porque hayan llevado algo a su final conceptual. Son maestros porque se dan cuenta que no existe uno. Pienso, mientras hablo de esto, en el porqué el entrenador de los arqueros me dijo al final de la práctica, lejos de los oídos de los arqueros, que él y sus colegas sienten que nunca pueden dar lo suficiente por sus equipos, sienten no hay suficientes técnicas de visualización ni entrenamientos de posturas con los que les ayuden a superar ese casi lograrlo. No sonaba como una queja, exactamente, sino como para dejarme saber, para admitir algo, para recordarme que se estaba entregando a una tarea voraz e incompleta que siempre requiere algo más. Nos construimos a partir de una idea inacabada, aún cuando esa idea sea nuestro anterior yo. Esta es la dinámica de la maestría. Acercarse a lo que pensaban que querían puede ayudarlos a obtener más de lo que nunca hayan soñado. Es lo que imagino que Elizabeth Murray pensaba cuando la vi sonreír sobre esas primeras obras en la galería. Aún si creamos utopías, creo que debemos dejarlas incompletas. La completud es la meta, pero espero que nunca sea el final. Gracias. (Aplausos)